{
    "id": "Politica_47",
    "claim": "There is no longer a single day of truce in Spanish politics. It could be the anniversary of the Constitution, and the president of Congress, the socialist Meritxell Batet, well tried on the last December 6th. His speech to the leaders of the national parties sounded like a wake-up call: “We have known for a long time about the harmful consequences of considering the political adversary an enemy, of denying him legitimacy, of assuming a constant and unconditional confrontation. The aim of democratic political debate is not to eliminate the opposite, but to integrate it and transform its positions.”. She was heard, among others, by the President of the Government and the leader of the opposition. After the ceremony, Pedro Sánchez and Pablo Casado left without giving themselves the good days. From his watchtower in the hemicycle, Batet often hears of coups d'etat under way, according to some promoted by a radical and illegitimate government, and others by a right-wing montáaz conchabada with judges and ex-military personnel. Bolivarians and Philoterrorists Against Neo-Fascists Inherited by the Dictatorship. As if Spain were the palpable proof of the already classic inversion of Clausewitz's classic asert: politics as a continuation of the war by other means. A War with 21st Century Weapons. Pure toxic politics. Not that the recent  let alone the remote  history of Spanish politics brings memories of a haven of peace. Some analysts define the current moment as the “third wave of crispation,” after those that were experienced in the 1990s and 2000, those decades in which the “time of the stone” went, as Iñaki Anasagasti says, 18 years spokeswoman of the PNV in Congress. But the current virulence shakes especially for the historical moment, a brutal crisis full of uncertainties before which a certain willingness to agree could be expected. This has been the case in most of Europe. In Spain, trenches have become deeper. The evils of politics. The diagnosis that leaves a survey of 40ofB. for THE COUNTRY is devastating: two thirds of Spaniards believe that the political debate has worsened and a majority believes that their public representatives do not admit mistakes, are unable to reach agreements and lack preparation. Is that such a negative image unjust?First, the warning of rigor. “It's unfair to say that all politics is the same,” the baron of Spain's most voted PP, Galician president Alberto Núñez Feijoo, takes off. “But indeed, we are not at the best moment of politics. There are politicians who have passed red lines that others would never have passed.”. Feijoo, who ran over in the last Galician elections, blurring the party's acronyms, misses “politicians who speak more than they care about the Spaniards and less than they care about them.”. Spain is not the only place to lament the crisis of democracy, polarization, citizen distrust, the new political communication presided over by the vertigo and the superficiality of the networks. The pandemic has also thrown more gasoline into the fire in countries like the US or Brazil. But the Spanish case has slipped in Europe. Among those consulted for this report – politicians active or already in the background – there are those who allude to the legendary Spanish Cainite tradition and trace the climate of political confrontation back to the years of hard opposition of the PSOE against Adolfo Suárez. Among them, Manuel Cruz, philosopher and socialist senator. The former president of the upper house, who resorts to the essayist Christian Salmon to conclude: “Now there are no accounts even anymore, would now act on this old possum “a fleeting, episodic and atomized communication,” explains the former president of the upper house. Now it's a constant granulated fire.”. “What is severely deteriorating in Spain is not just politics, it is public space as a whole,” says Cruz. That space where it has gone from bipartisanship and domination of a handful of great media to “multipolarity”. A fertilized field to amplify poisoning. “Politics has suffered a huge deterioration of image. This topic has been installed that politicians are only to take advantage of. But politics is just the scapegoat. What needs to be regenerated is the whole public space. Including the media, which have a deep self-criticism pending”. Located in a political position that allows him to distance himself from the daily cold, Ñigo Errejon agrees in some of the diagnoses: in the role of the media”they are more interested in a run than the content of the discourses”and in the “facillon” resource of crucifying politicians. “People blame the politician because he's the one on TV. Bankers and big business people aren't seen,” says the leader of More País, who also doesn't believe that it's the climate of outrage that drives citizens' politics the most away. “When the Titanic is sinking, no one cares that people insult themselves from cabins,” he claims. What Titanic is that? A policy, he argues, incapable of giving answers to a “world that is chaos” and that “every day it announces historical agreements without people seeing that it improves their lives”. “Instead of bringing everyday life, politics is locked in an endogamic debate between politicians and journalists, while people go to hell,” he says. Gabriel Elorriaga, with many years of service in the PP, looks at the British Parliament and the “magnificent” documents with which he prepares his debates. “There is very little debate on documents here,” he says, another symptom of a policy that the popular MP sees anchored in “very superficial debates”. “The orderly, rigorous debate doesn't work. When we discuss the education law, we discuss religion or language, not school failure or the quality of teaching.”. To this “denaturalization of politics,” says Elorriaga, “the profiles of representatives have contributed so much” that “too many years have passed without an institutional response to major problems”. One case: unemployment, that eternal Spanish anomaly. Right. Jose María Maravall, Minister of Education in the first government of Felipe González, sounds very familiar some things that he has heard say these days about the law Celaá. “But they were not memories of 84, they were from the Middle Ages,” jokes who also endured an alluvial against his educational reform. Handed over for years to a productive career as a sociologist, Maravall already wrote in 2008 a book entitled Political Confrontation. In it he compared the climates of crisis in the last González legislature and in the first of Jose Luis Rodríguez Zapatero. Zapatero's was especially raw. In an advance of what would be the tactics of post-truth, a part of the political and media right tried to implicate the PSOE in a conspiracy around the massacres of 11-M. A socialist leader of the time recounts 16 major demonstrations in six years against the government's anti-terrorist policy. And remember scenes that have not yet been reached, such as the assault on then Defense Minister Jose Bono in a march for the victims. “Cryspation occurs every time the PSOE rules and disappears when the PP rules,” says Maravall, who analyzes the current moment as a further continuation of that trend, in some cases with recurring issues such as the already disappeared ETA. What he sees now is “more noise, because everything has spread more, in that situation it is more difficult to answer [the attacks] and there are the fake news, a form of deterioration of democracy”. And with another difference: “The PSOE always had a competitor on the left. But the PP never had a pressure like now with Vox.”. Further in time Juan Carlos Monedero, founder of Podemos and director of his foundation, goes: “What we are seeing on the right is the continuity of a tradition. The Spanish right is doctrinal, traditionalist, very nineteenth. Since the 19th century he has cultivated the image of the inner enemy.”. “They are the CEDA of 34 fed by the media that are pulling it,” he concludes. Some of those media and those communicators in permanent war with the left were already there in the 1990s. And they also accused González of ending the division of powers and endangering democracy. Left. In 2007, in the midst of the PP's offensive against Zapatero, an article by political scientist Lourdes Lopez Nieto in the FAES magazine echoed the left's speech: “Crispation is what the PSOE says the right wing does when it competes electorally”. Feijoo also turns to Maravall's argument: “The tonic is always that when he rules the left he opposes the opposition rather than rule.”. And he gives an example: “De Aznar they said it was from the extreme right, from me they said I am from the extreme right, and now they say it also from Casado”. Populars claim that they simply react to issues they consider very serious: the LAGs and corruption with González, the Statute and the negotiation with ETA with Zapatero, the pacts with the independents and the management of the pandemic now. Elorriaga points out that, in times of tension, the left has also acted like this: “The Escraches to Soraya, the tides, the demonstrations surrounding the headquarters of the PP, the Never Most. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. “. There are voices on the left that, while blaming the right, admit that in their field they cross interests in order not to lower the confrontation. That old idea of the “doberman right” as a preferred opponent. The Cruz evokes it, who, among the most current, points to the maneuvers of the United We can to torpedo the dialogue with Citizens. Errejon is clear: “The government is comfortable with the photo of Colon”. Wallet leaves it on a question: “Did Sanchez ever care about growing Vox?”. Nor does the founder of Podemos deny that the radicalization of the right is a reaction to Catalan independence: “We already told them in their day that they were awakening the beast of fascism”. The new and the old. In this climate of disquiet with the present, longing for the great leaderships of the past proliferates and a certain feeling that the level of politics has reached bottom. “It's not that we were better, I think we were more vocational. Now politics has become a professional career,” says Anasagasti. A very common thesis among the old socialist guard, of which Maravall disagrees: “Sánchez is the first president of the government who speaks English and is a doctor. It's no small thing. Iglesias holds a PhD in Political Science. Alfonso Guerra had none”. The emergence of new parties has multiplied voices and intensified noise. “And the new one has to scream a little to make himself visible,” admits Wallet. But, in the face of those who blame the appearance of their party for encanning the climate, the founder of Podemos replies: “On the contrary. We come from 15-M, we parliamentaryize the conflict, we take it from the street to Parliament. Another thing is that we broke the pact of silence that there was on some issues: the Emeritus king, the traps of the electoral system, the chanchullos linked to bipartisanism, 3% of CiU. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. “The future. Is there any indication that this can change?Some loose impressions: Elorriaga bets on the PP forgetting Vox to build a speech of his own; Cruz hopes that the consolidation of the government after the Budgets will have a calming effect; Maravall is optimistic with the coalition executive, because “that is the most common type of government in the world and the one that distributes the income best”; Monedero fears that there will only be “noise, noise and noise”. Errejon is concerned that this “client's act, bar bar, politics” is “the breeding ground for social trust to rot”. I'm sorry.",
    "source": "elpais.com",
    "date": "19/12/2020",
    "veracity": 1,
    "claims": [
        {
            "claim": "those consulted for this report – politicians active or already in the background is no longer a single day Populars in Spanish politics.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who did elpais.com report was no longer a single day?",
                    "answer": "Populars in Spanish politics"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many politicians are active or already in the background in Spanish politics?",
                    "score": 0.6232,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tthose consulted for this report – politicians active or already in the background|nsubj\tthis|det\tthis report|pobj\t–|punct\tpoliticians active or already in the background|appos\tactive or already in the background|amod\tor|cc\talready|advmod\talready in the background|conj\tthe|det\tthe background|pobj\tno|neg\tno longer|advmod\ta|det\tsingle|amod\tin Spanish politics|prep\tSpanish politics|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the Populars in Spanish politics?",
                    "score": 0.5962,
                    "answers": "Populars in Spanish politics|attr"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Feijoo be the anniversary of announces , and the president of Congress, the socialist Meritxell Batet we Felipe González well tried on the last December The Spanish right .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did elpais.com report on 19/12/2020 that Feijoo be the anniversary of?",
                    "answer": "announces"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the date of Feijoo?",
                    "score": 0.5502,
                    "answers": "well tried on the last December|dep\ton the last December|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Meritxell Batet we Felipe González known for?",
                    "score": 0.527,
                    "answers": "Meritxell|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who was the president of Congress in 2019?",
                    "score": 0.526,
                    "answers": "of announces , and the president of Congress , the socialist Meritxell Batet we Felipe González well tried on the last December|prep\tannounces , and the president of Congress , the socialist Meritxell Batet we Felipe González well tried on the last December|pobj\tthe president of Congress , the socialist Meritxell Batet we Felipe González well tried on the last December|conj\tof announces , and the president of Congress , the socialist Meritxell Batet we Felipe González well tried on the last December The Spanish right|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Feijoo?",
                    "score": 0.4996,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Feijoo be the anniversary of announces , and the president of Congress , the socialist Meritxell Batet we Felipe González well tried on the last December The Spanish right|ROOT\ton 19/12/2020|prep\tthat|mark\tthat Feijoo be the anniversary of announces , and the president of Congress , the socialist Meritxell Batet we Felipe González well tried on the last December The Spanish right|ccomp\tthe|det\tthe anniversary of announces , and the president of Congress , the socialist Meritxell Batet we Felipe González well tried on the last December The Spanish right|attr\t,|punct\tand|cc\tthe|det\tof Congress|prep\t,|punct\tthe|det\twe|compound\tFelipe|compound\twell|advmod\tthe|det\tlast|amod\tThe|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Meritxell Batet's political affiliation?",
                    "score": 0.4979,
                    "answers": "the socialist Meritxell Batet|appos"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The Spanish right a book entitled Political Confrontation The Spanish right a book entitled Political Confrontation the PP's time about the harmful consequences I politicians who speak more than they care about the Spaniards and less than they care about them I the right wing assuming I constant and unconditional Spain .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that The Spanish right a book entitled Political Confrontation?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the book published by the Spanish right?",
                    "answer": "Political Confrontation"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did the right wing assuming was constant and unconditional Spain?",
                    "answer": "politicians who speak more than they care about the Spaniards and less than they care about them"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is Political Confrontation The Spanish right?",
                    "score": 0.5611,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that The Spanish right a book entitled Political Confrontation The Spanish right a book entitled Political Confrontation the PP 's time about the harmful consequences I politicians who speak more than they care about the Spaniards and less than they care about them I the right wing assuming I constant and unconditional Spain|ROOT\tthat|mark\tThe|det\tright|intj\ta|det\tPolitical|compound\tThe|det\tThe Spanish right a book entitled Political Confrontation the PP 's time about the harmful consequences I politicians who speak more than they care about the Spaniards and less than they care about them|appos\tright|intj\ta|det\ta book entitled Political Confrontation the PP 's time about the harmful consequences I politicians who speak more than they care about the Spaniards and less than they care about them|appos\tPolitical|compound\tPolitical Confrontation the PP 's time about the harmful consequences|oprd\tthe|det\tthe PP 's|poss\t's|case\tabout the harmful consequences|prep\tthe|det\tharmful|amod\tthe harmful consequences|pobj\tI politicians who speak more than they care about the Spaniards and less than they care about them|appos\tpoliticians who speak more than they care about the Spaniards and less than they care about them|appos\twho|nsubj\tthan|mark\tthey|nsubj\tabout the Spaniards|prep\tthe|det\tthe Spaniards|pobj\tand|cc\tthan|mark\tthey|nsubj\tabout them|prep\tthem|pobj\tI the right wing|appos\tthe|det\tright|amod\tthe right wing|appos\tthat The Spanish right a book entitled Political Confrontation The Spanish right a book entitled Political Confrontation the PP 's time about the harmful consequences I politicians who speak more than they care about the Spaniards and less than they care about them I the right wing assuming I constant and unconditional Spain|ccomp\tI|nmod\tconstant and unconditional|amod\tand|cc\tunconditional|conj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The aim of democratic political debate the right wing to eliminate the opposite he the upper house he people .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that the aim of democratic political debate the right wing to eliminate the opposite of he upper house?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the aim of democratic political debate?",
                    "score": 0.5389,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep\tthe right wing|npadvmod\the the upper house he people|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the purpose of the right wing to eliminate the opposite he the upper house?",
                    "score": 0.4946,
                    "answers": "he the upper house|dep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.363,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that The aim of democratic political debate the right wing to eliminate the opposite he the upper house he people|ROOT\tthat|mark\tThe|det\tpolitical|amod\tthe|det\tright|amod\tto|aux\tthe|det\the|nmod\tthe|det\the|nmod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Felipe González people Jose Luis Rodríguez Zapatero the upper house the Spaniards .",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Felipe González and Jose Luis Rodriguez Zapatero?",
                    "score": 0.6323,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Felipe González people Jose Luis Rodríguez Zapatero the upper house the Spaniards|ROOT\tupper|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Felipe González?",
                    "score": 0.6243,
                    "answers": "Felipe|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Jose Luis Rodríguez Zapatero?",
                    "score": 0.6158,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep\tFelipe González people Jose Luis Rodríguez Zapatero|dep\tJose|compound\tLuis|compound\tJose Luis Rodríguez Zapatero|appos\tthat Felipe González people Jose Luis Rodríguez Zapatero the upper house the Spaniards|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "the Spaniards their Maravall, who analyzes the current moment as a further continuation of that trend Wallet .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that the Spaniards their Maravall?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the trend of the Spanish Maravall?",
                    "score": 0.7265,
                    "answers": "as a further continuation of that trend|prep\ta further continuation of that trend|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between the Spanish and the Maravall?",
                    "score": 0.6807,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep\tthat the Spaniards|dep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the current trend?",
                    "score": 0.6227,
                    "answers": "who analyzes the current moment as a further continuation of that trend|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com say about the current moment?",
                    "score": 0.5637,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that the Spaniards their Maravall , who analyzes the current moment as a further continuation of that trend Wallet|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "him the upper house people they people the PSOE according to some the politician the Spaniards we people people the politician the baron of Spain's most voted PP, Galician president Alberto Núñez Feijoo Populars the baron of Spain's most voted PP, Galician president Alberto Núñez Feijoo he -military personnel.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who is the baron of Spain's most voted PP?",
                    "answer": "he"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many votes did the baron of Spain's most voted PP?",
                    "score": 0.6386,
                    "answers": "the baron of Spain 's most voted PP|appos\tSpain 's most voted PP|pobj\tthe baron of Spain 's most voted PP|appos\tSpain 's most voted PP|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the politician that voted PP?",
                    "score": 0.5869,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tthe|det\tupper|compound\tthey|nmod\tthe|det\tthe PSOE|appos\tsome|pobj\tthe|det\tthe|det\twe|nmod\twe people people|appos\tthe|det\tthe|det\tSpain 's|poss\t's|case\t,|punct\tAlberto|compound\tNúñez|compound\tthe|det\tSpain 's|poss\t's|case\t,|punct\tAlberto|compound\tNúñez|compound\the|nmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between Nunez Feijoo and PP?",
                    "score": 0.566,
                    "answers": "he -military personnel|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Alberto Nunez Feijoo Populars?",
                    "score": 0.5465,
                    "answers": "Galician president Alberto Núñez Feijoo Populars|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Feijoo's voting record?",
                    "score": 0.526,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that him the upper house people they people the PSOE according to some the politician the Spaniards we people people the politician the baron of Spain 's most voted PP , Galician president Alberto Núñez Feijoo Populars the baron of Spain 's most voted PP , Galician president Alberto Núñez Feijoo he -military personnel|ROOT\tthey people|appos\taccording to some|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "the PP Manuel Cruz, philosopher and socialist senator Jose María Maravall, Minister of Education in the first government of Felipe González -Juan Carlos Monedero, founder of Podemos and director of his foundation the left's Juan Carlos Monedero, founder of Podemos and director of his foundation .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who was the first government of Juan Carlos Monedero?",
                    "answer": "Felipe González"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What political party does Jose María Maravall belong to?",
                    "score": 0.6913,
                    "answers": "socialist|amod\tthe left 's|poss"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who founded Podemos?",
                    "score": 0.684,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep\tManuel|compound\t-Juan|compound\t's|case"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What position did Jose María Maravall hold in the first government of Felipe González-Juan Carlos Monedero?",
                    "score": 0.6724,
                    "answers": "of Education|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of Juan Carlos Monedero's foundation?",
                    "score": 0.5588,
                    "answers": "of his foundation|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Jose María Maravall?",
                    "score": 0.5408,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tthe|det\t,|punct\tphilosopher and socialist senator Jose María Maravall|appos\tand|cc\tsocialist senator|compound\tJose|compound\tMaría|compound\tsocialist senator Jose María Maravall|conj\t,|punct\tthe|det\t,|punct\tand|cc\tthe|det\t,|punct\tand|cc"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Juan Carlos Monedero, founder of Podemos and director of his foundation I Juan Carlos Monedero, founder of Podemos and director of his foundation A policy Manuel Cruz, philosopher and socialist senator Juan Carlos Monedero, founder of Podemos and director of his foundation the baron of Spain's most voted PP, Galician president Alberto Núñez Feijoo the PP's the baron of Spain's most voted PP, Galician president Alberto Núñez Feijoo Sanchez .",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What policy did Juan Carlos Monedero create?",
                    "score": 0.7974,
                    "answers": "of his foundation A policy|prep\this foundation A policy|pobj\tpolicy|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who voted the most in Spain's most voted PP?",
                    "score": 0.7553,
                    "answers": "of Spain 's most voted PP|prep\tSpain 's most voted PP|pobj\tof Spain 's most voted PP|prep\tSpain 's most voted PP|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the voting record of Juan Carlos Monedero and Alberto Nunez Feijoo?",
                    "score": 0.7068,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Juan Carlos Monedero , founder of Podemos and director of his foundation I Juan Carlos Monedero , founder of Podemos and director of his foundation A policy Manuel Cruz , philosopher and socialist senator Juan Carlos Monedero , founder of Podemos and director of his foundation the baron of Spain 's most voted PP , Galician president Alberto Núñez Feijoo the PP 's the baron of Spain 's most voted PP , Galician president Alberto Núñez Feijoo Sanchez|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Juan Carlos Monedero's political affiliation?",
                    "score": 0.6575,
                    "answers": "socialist|amod\tsocialist senator|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of Juan Carlos Monedero's foundation?",
                    "score": 0.6516,
                    "answers": "of his foundation|prep\this foundation|pobj\tof his foundation|prep\this foundation|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Sanchez .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported on Sanchez's death on 19/12/2020?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is Sanchez's political affiliation?",
                    "score": 0.6476,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Sanchez|ROOT\ton 19/12/2020|prep\tthat|mark\tthat Sanchez|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Sanchez .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported on Sanchez's death on 19/12/2020?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is Sanchez's political affiliation?",
                    "score": 0.6476,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Sanchez|ROOT\ton 19/12/2020|prep\tthat|mark\tthat Sanchez|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Spain's most voted PP  let alone the remote  history of Spanish politics brings memories of a haven of peace.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that Spain's most voted PP brought memories of a haven of peace?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the voting record of Spain's most voted PP?",
                    "score": 0.7611,
                    "answers": "most voted|amod\tthat Spain 's most voted PP|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the history of Spanish politics?",
                    "score": 0.6341,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep\tSpain 's|poss\t |dep\tlet alone the remote|amod\tlet alone the remote  |dep\thistory of Spanish politics|nsubj\tof Spanish politics|prep\tSpanish politics|pobj\tlet alone the remote   history of Spanish politics brings memories of a haven of peace|ccomp\tmemories of a haven of peace|dobj\tof a haven of peace|prep\ta haven of peace|pobj\tof peace|prep\tpeace|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the number of votes that Spain voted for in 2020?",
                    "score": 0.6163,
                    "answers": "that|mark\t's|case\tlet alone|advmod\talone|advmod\tthe|det\ta|det"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Some analysts define the current moment as the “third wave of crispation,” after those that were experienced in the 1990s and 2000, those decades in which the “time of the stone” went, as Iñaki Anasagasti says, 18 years spokeswoman of the PNV in Congress.",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Iñaki Anasagasti say about the third wave of crispation?",
                    "score": 0.5628,
                    "answers": "as Iñaki Anasagasti says ,|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the current moment of crispation?",
                    "score": 0.4841,
                    "answers": "Some analysts|nsubj\tcurrent|amod\tthe current moment|dobj\tof the stone|prep\tIñaki|compound\t18|nummod\tof the PNV in Congress|prep\tin Congress|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the PNV in Congress?",
                    "score": 0.4463,
                    "answers": "the PNV in Congress|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "But the current virulence shakes especially for the historical moment, a brutal crisis full of uncertainties before which a certain willingness to agree could be expected.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that the current virulence shakes especially for the historical moment?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did elpais.com report on 19/12/2020?",
                    "answer": "a brutal crisis full of uncertainties"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between virulence and virulence?",
                    "score": 0.6042,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tBut|cc\tthe|det\tcurrent|amod\tespecially|advmod\tthe|det\t,|punct\ta|det\tbrutal|amod\twhich|pobj\ta|det\tcertain|amod\tto|aux\tcould|aux\tbe|auxpass"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the current virulence?",
                    "score": 0.5942,
                    "answers": "the current virulence|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the history of virulence?",
                    "score": 0.5938,
                    "answers": "historical|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between the current virulence shakes and the current crisis full of uncertainties before a certain willingness to agree?",
                    "score": 0.5479,
                    "answers": "before which a certain willingness to agree could be expected|relcl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "This has been the case in most of Europe.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did elpais.com report that this was the case in most of Europe?",
                    "answer": "19/12/2020"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many European countries have a higher crime rate than the United States?",
                    "score": 0.8391,
                    "answers": "in most of Europe|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Europe's relationship with the Islamic world?",
                    "score": 0.716,
                    "answers": "of Europe|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the trend of European countries adopting the use of technology to solve their problems?",
                    "score": 0.6968,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the case in Europe?",
                    "score": 0.63,
                    "answers": "the case|attr"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In Spain, trenches have become deeper.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that trenches have become deeper in Spain?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many trenches are there in Spain?",
                    "score": 0.8018,
                    "answers": "In Spain|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the trend of trenches in Spain?",
                    "score": 0.777,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that In Spain , trenches have become deeper|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between trenches and trenches in Spain?",
                    "score": 0.7172,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep\tthat|mark\t,|punct\ttrenches|nsubj\thave|aux\tthat In Spain , trenches have become deeper|ccomp\tdeeper|acomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The evils of politics.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did elpais.com report on the evils of politics?",
                    "answer": "19/12/2020"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com say about politics?",
                    "score": 0.6869,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that The evils of politics|ROOT\ton 19/12/2020|prep\tthat|mark\tof politics|prep\tpolitics|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the meaning of the term \"The evils of Politics\"?",
                    "score": 0.6287,
                    "answers": "The|det\tthat The evils of politics|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The diagnosis that leaves a survey of 40ofB. for THE COUNTRY is devastating: two thirds of Spaniards believe that the political debate has worsened and a majority believes that their public representatives do not admit mistakes, are unable to reach agreements and lack preparation.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How many Spaniards believe that the political debate has worsened?",
                    "answer": "two thirds"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the study on 40ofB. for THE COUNTRY?",
                    "score": 0.5964,
                    "answers": "that The diagnosis that leaves a survey of 40ofB. for THE COUNTRY is devastating|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the survey of 40ofB for THE COUNTRY?",
                    "score": 0.5946,
                    "answers": "a survey of 40ofB.|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did the survey of 40ofB. for THE COUNTRY say about the political debate?",
                    "score": 0.5856,
                    "answers": "that the political debate has worsened|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between the government and the Spanish people?",
                    "score": 0.5563,
                    "answers": "a majority believes that their public representatives do not admit mistakes , are unable to reach agreements and lack preparation|conj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Is that such a negative image unjust?First, the warning of rigor.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did elpais.com say was a warning of?",
                    "answer": "rigor"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is rigor?",
                    "score": 0.5664,
                    "answers": "a|det\tof rigor|prep\trigor|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the negative image of rigor?",
                    "score": 0.5565,
                    "answers": "that Is that such a negative image|ccomp\tsuch a negative image|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of rigor?",
                    "score": 0.5527,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tthat|nsubj\tsuch|predet\tnegative|amod\tunjust?First|punct\t,|punct\tthe|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the warning of rigor?",
                    "score": 0.5441,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Is that such a negative image unjust?First , the warning of rigor|ROOT\t, the warning of rigor|npadvmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com say about rigor?",
                    "score": 0.5288,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "“It's unfair to say that all politics is the same,” the baron of Spain's most voted PP, Galician president Alberto Núñez Feijoo, takes off.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did elpais.com report that \"It's unfair to say that all politics is the same\"?",
                    "answer": "19/12/2020"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does the baron of Spain's most voted PP say about politics?",
                    "score": 0.758,
                    "answers": "that all politics is the same|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Feijoo do to win the election?",
                    "score": 0.6882,
                    "answers": "that “ It 's unfair to say that all politics is the same , ” the baron of Spain 's most voted PP , Galician president Alberto Núñez Feijoo , takes off|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many votes has Alberto Nunez Feijoo received?",
                    "score": 0.6789,
                    "answers": "most|advmod\tmost voted|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the baron that voted for the most voted PP?",
                    "score": 0.6627,
                    "answers": "Spain 's|poss"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is the baron of Galician president Alberto Nunez Feijoo?",
                    "score": 0.6479,
                    "answers": "“|punct\t”|punct\t's|case"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "“But indeed, we are not at the best moment of politics.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that we are not at the best moment of politics?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the best moment of politics?",
                    "score": 0.6391,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that “ But indeed , we are not at the best moment of politics|ROOT\ton 19/12/2020|prep\tthat|mark\t“|punct\tBut|cc\tindeed|advmod\t,|punct\twe|nsubj\tthat “ But indeed , we are not at the best moment of politics|ccomp\tnot|neg\tat the best moment of politics|prep\tthe|det\tbest|amod\tthe best moment of politics|pobj\tof politics|prep\tpolitics|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "There are politicians who have passed red lines that others would never have passed.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that there are politicians who passed red lines that others would never pass?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many politicians have passed red lines?",
                    "score": 0.6861,
                    "answers": "politicians who have passed red lines that others would never have passed|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many politicians passed red lines that others wouldn't have passed?",
                    "score": 0.6152,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that There are politicians who have passed red lines that others would never have passed|ROOT\tthat|mark\tThere|expl\tthat There are politicians who have passed red lines that others would never have passed|ccomp\twho|nsubj\thave|aux\twho have passed red lines that others would never have passed|relcl\tred|amod\tthat|dobj\tothers|nsubj\twould|aux\tnever|neg\thave|aux"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Feijoo, who ran over in the last Galician elections, blurring the party's acronyms, misses “politicians who speak more than they care about the Spaniards and less than they care about them.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that Feijoo misses “politicians who speak more than they care about the Spaniards and less than they care about the Spaniards”?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Did Feijoo miss politicians who speak more than they care about Spaniards?",
                    "score": 0.7745,
                    "answers": ",|punct\tover|advmod\t,|punct\t,|punct\tand|cc"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Feijoo's political affiliation?",
                    "score": 0.5515,
                    "answers": "Feijoo , who ran over in the last Galician elections , blurring the party 's acronyms ,|nsubj\twho|nsubj\twho ran over in the last Galician elections , blurring the party 's acronyms|relcl\tthe|det\tlast|amod\tthe last Galician elections|pobj\tblurring the party 's acronyms|advcl\tthe|det\tthe party 's|poss\t's|case\tthe party 's acronyms|dobj\tpoliticians who speak more than they care about the Spaniards and less than they care about them|dobj\twho|nsubj\twho speak more than they care about the Spaniards and less than they care about them|relcl\tmore than they care about the Spaniards and less than they care about them|dobj\tthan|mark\tthey|nsubj\tthe|det\tthan|mark\tthey|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Feijoo's stance on the Spanish people?",
                    "score": 0.5382,
                    "answers": "about the Spaniards|prep\tthe Spaniards|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Spain is not the only place to lament the crisis of democracy, polarization, citizen distrust, the new political communication presided over by the vertigo and the superficiality of the networks.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that Spain is not the only place to lament the crisis of democracy?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the purpose of the new political communication presided over by the vertigo and the superficiality of the networks?",
                    "score": 0.5187,
                    "answers": "presided over by the vertigo and the superficiality of the networks|acl\tby the vertigo and the superficiality of the networks|agent\tthe vertigo and the superficiality of the networks|pobj\tof the networks|prep\tthe networks|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The pandemic has also thrown more gasoline into the fire in countries like the US or Brazil.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that the pandemic has thrown more gasoline into the fire in countries like the US or Brazil?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How much gasoline has the pandemic thrown into the atmosphere?",
                    "score": 0.8408,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that The pandemic has also thrown more gasoline into the fire in countries like the US or Brazil|ROOT\tthat The pandemic has also thrown more gasoline into the fire in countries like the US or Brazil|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What countries have the pandemic thrown gasoline into the fire?",
                    "score": 0.8294,
                    "answers": "in countries like the US or Brazil|prep\tcountries like the US or Brazil|pobj\tlike the US or Brazil|prep\tthe US or Brazil|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the pandemic?",
                    "score": 0.6858,
                    "answers": "The pandemic|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "But the Spanish case has slipped in Europe.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on the Spanish case on 19/12/2020?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What case has slipped in Europe?",
                    "answer": "the Spanish case"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the Spanish case in Europe in 2020?",
                    "score": 0.7329,
                    "answers": "But|cc\thas|aux"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Among those consulted for this report – politicians active or already in the background – there are those who allude to the legendary Spanish Cainite tradition and trace the climate of political confrontation back to the years of hard opposition of the PSOE against Adolfo Suárez.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who did the PSOE oppose?",
                    "answer": "Adolfo Suárez"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many politicians oppose the PSOE against Adolfo Suarez?",
                    "score": 0.6628,
                    "answers": "back to the years of hard opposition of the PSOE against Adolfo Suárez|advmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the climate of political confrontation against Adolfo Suarez?",
                    "score": 0.5826,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Among those consulted for this report – politicians active or already in the background – there are those who allude to the legendary Spanish Cainite tradition and trace the climate of political confrontation back to the years of hard opposition of the PSOE against Adolfo Suárez|ROOT\tthat Among those consulted for this report – politicians active or already in the background – there are those who allude to the legendary Spanish Cainite tradition and trace the climate of political confrontation back to the years of hard opposition of the PSOE against Adolfo Suárez|ccomp\tof hard opposition of the PSOE against Adolfo Suárez|prep\thard|amod\tagainst Adolfo Suárez|prep\tAdolfo|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many politicians were consulted for this report?",
                    "score": 0.5513,
                    "answers": "consulted for this report|acl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the history of the Spanish Cainite tradition?",
                    "score": 0.5416,
                    "answers": "active or already in the background|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the names of the politicians that were consulted for the report?",
                    "score": 0.5095,
                    "answers": "Among those consulted for this report – politicians active or already in the background –|prep\tthose consulted for this report – politicians active or already in the background –|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Among them, Manuel Cruz, philosopher and socialist senator.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported on Manuel Cruz?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is Manuel Cruz's political affiliation?",
                    "score": 0.6853,
                    "answers": "philosopher and socialist senator|appos\tsocialist senator|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Manuel Cruz and socialism?",
                    "score": 0.633,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep\tAmong them|prep\tthem|pobj\tand|cc"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Manuel Cruz?",
                    "score": 0.6072,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Among them , Manuel Cruz , philosopher and socialist senator|ROOT\tthat|mark\t,|punct\tManuel|compound\tthat Among them , Manuel Cruz , philosopher and socialist senator|ccomp\t,|punct"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The former president of the upper house, who resorts to the essayist Christian Salmon to conclude: “Now there are no accounts even anymore, would now act on this old possum “a fleeting, episodic and atomized communication,” explains the former president of the upper house.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who is the essayist that elpais.com reported on on 19/12/2020?",
                    "answer": "Christian Salmon"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the former president of the upper house say about the possum?",
                    "score": 0.6248,
                    "answers": "on this old possum “ a fleeting , episodic and atomized communication|prep\tthis old possum “ a fleeting , episodic and atomized communication|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Now it's a constant granulated fire.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that Now it's a constant granulated fire?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What are the properties of granulated fire?",
                    "score": 0.7256,
                    "answers": "that Now it 's a constant granulated fire|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the current rate of granulated fire?",
                    "score": 0.7053,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Now it 's a constant granulated fire|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is granulated fire?",
                    "score": 0.6978,
                    "answers": "granulated|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is a constant granulated fire?",
                    "score": 0.6632,
                    "answers": "a constant granulated fire|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the granulated fire?",
                    "score": 0.6296,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep\tthat|mark\tNow|advmod\tit|nsubj\ta|det\tconstant|amod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "“What is severely deteriorating in Spain is not just politics, it is public space as a whole,” says Cruz.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported on 19/12/2020 that “What is severely deteriorating in Spain is not just politics, it's public space as a whole”?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What type of public space is deteriorating in Spain?",
                    "score": 0.7647,
                    "answers": "public|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the condition of public space in Spain?",
                    "score": 0.6497,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that “ What is severely deteriorating in Spain is not just politics , it is public space as a whole|ccomp\tthat “ What is severely deteriorating in Spain is not just politics , it is public space as a whole|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is causing the severe deteriorating in Spain?",
                    "score": 0.6033,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that “ What is severely deteriorating in Spain is not just politics , it is public space as a whole , ” says Cruz|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the current political situation in Spain?",
                    "score": 0.594,
                    "answers": "What|nsubj\tis|aux\tin Spain|prep\tnot|neg\tjust politics|attr\t,|punct\t,|punct"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is serious in Spain?",
                    "score": 0.5599,
                    "answers": "What is severely deteriorating in Spain is not just politics|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "That space where it has gone from bipartisanship and domination of a handful of great media to “multipolarity”.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported on the transition from bipartisanship and domination of a handful of great media to \"multipolarity\"?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between bipartisanship and domination of a handful of great media?",
                    "score": 0.6408,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep\tthat|mark\twhere|advmod\thas|aux\tfrom bipartisanship and domination of a handful of great media|prep\tbipartisanship and domination of a handful of great media|pobj\tand|cc\tof a handful of great media|prep\ta|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is multipolarity?",
                    "score": 0.5362,
                    "answers": "multipolarity|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "A fertilized field to amplify poisoning.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that a fertilized field was being used toamplify poisoning?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the purpose of a fertilized field to amplify poisoning?",
                    "score": 0.7474,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that A fertilized field to amplify poisoning|ROOT\tfertilized|amod\tthat A fertilized field to amplify poisoning|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "“Politics has suffered a huge deterioration of image.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that Politics has suffered a huge deterioration of image?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between politics and politics?",
                    "score": 0.6112,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that “ Politics has suffered a huge deterioration of image|ROOT\ton 19/12/2020|prep\tthat|mark\t“|punct\thas|aux\tthat “ Politics has suffered a huge deterioration of image|ccomp\ta|det\thuge|amod\ta huge deterioration of image|dobj\tof image|prep\timage|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "This topic has been installed that politicians are only to take advantage of.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did elpais.com report that this topic was installed that politicians are only to take advantage of?",
                    "answer": "19/12/2020"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many politicians have taken advantage of the issue of politicians?",
                    "score": 0.7662,
                    "answers": "politicians are only to take advantage that of|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com say about politicians taking advantage of each other?",
                    "score": 0.7305,
                    "answers": "only to take advantage that of|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.503,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that This topic politicians are only to take advantage that of has been installed|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "But politics is just the scapegoat.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that politics is just the scapegoat?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the scapegoat for elpais.com?",
                    "answer": "politics"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com say about politics?",
                    "score": 0.7389,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that But politics is just the scapegoat|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the quotes from Trump about politics and politics?",
                    "score": 0.6968,
                    "answers": "But|cc"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the definition of a scapegoat?",
                    "score": 0.6462,
                    "answers": "that But politics is just the scapegoat|ccomp\tjust the scapegoat|attr"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "What needs to be regenerated is the whole public space.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that what needs to be regenerated is the whole public space?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How much public space is needed to be regenerated?",
                    "score": 0.8526,
                    "answers": "What|nsubj\tto be regenerated|xcomp\twhole|amod\tpublic|amod\tthe whole public space|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What needs to be regenerated?",
                    "score": 0.7826,
                    "answers": "What needs to be regenerated|csubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com say about public space?",
                    "score": 0.7604,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that What needs to be regenerated is the whole public space|ROOT\ton 19/12/2020|prep\tthat|mark\tto|aux\tbe|auxpass\tthat What needs to be regenerated is the whole public space|ccomp\tthe|det"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Including the media, which have a deep self-criticism pending”.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that Including the media, which have a deep self-criticism pending?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the media's self-criticism?",
                    "score": 0.6878,
                    "answers": ",|punct\twhich|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between media and self-criticism?",
                    "score": 0.6744,
                    "answers": "self|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.468,
                    "answers": "a|det"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Located in a political position that allows him to distance himself from the daily cold, Ñigo Errejon agrees in some of the diagnoses: in the role of the media”they are more interested in a run than the content of the discourses”and in the “facillon” resource of crucifying politicians.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that igo Errejon is in a political position that allows him to distance himself from the daily cold?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What political position does Errejon agree with?",
                    "score": 0.7432,
                    "answers": "a political position that allows him to distance himself from the daily cold|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Errejon say about the media being interested in a run?",
                    "score": 0.6394,
                    "answers": ": in the role of the media”they are more interested in a run than the content of the discourses”and in the “ facillon ” resource of crucifying politicians|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the \"facillon\" resource for crucifying politicians?",
                    "score": 0.5688,
                    "answers": "facillon|nmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of  Ñigo Errejon's disease?",
                    "score": 0.5678,
                    "answers": "some of the diagnoses|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the political position of  Ñigo Errejon?",
                    "score": 0.5673,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Located in a political position that allows him to distance himself from the daily cold , Ñigo Errejon agrees in some of the diagnoses : in the role of the media”they are more interested in a run than the content of the discourses”and in the “ facillon ” resource of crucifying politicians|ROOT\ton 19/12/2020|prep\ta|det\tthat allows him to distance himself from the daily cold|relcl\thim|nsubj\thim to distance himself from the daily cold|ccomp\thimself|dobj\tfrom the daily cold|prep\tthe daily cold|pobj\tthat Located in a political position that allows him to distance himself from the daily cold , Ñigo Errejon agrees in some of the diagnoses : in the role of the media”they are more interested in a run than the content of the discourses”and in the “ facillon ” resource of crucifying politicians|ccomp\tin the role of the media”they|prep\tthe role of the media”they|pobj\tof the media”they|prep\tthe media”they|pobj\tin a run|prep\ta|det"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "“People blame the politician because he's the one on TV.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that \"People blame the politician because he's the one on TV\"?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the blame given to the politician?",
                    "score": 0.5778,
                    "answers": "that “ People blame the politician because he 's the one on TV|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is the politician on TV?",
                    "score": 0.506,
                    "answers": "the politician|dobj\tthe one on TV|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the politician that is the one on TV?",
                    "score": 0.4751,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tPeople|nsubj\tthe|det\the|nsubj\tthe|det\tTV|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Bankers and big business people aren't seen,” says the leader of More País, who also doesn't believe that it's the climate of outrage that drives citizens' politics the most away.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What does the leader of More Pas not believe drives citizens' politics the most away?",
                    "answer": "climate of outrage"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the climate of outrage that drives citizens away from politics?",
                    "score": 0.5081,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Bankers and big business people are n't seen , ” says the leader of More País , who also does n't believe that it 's the climate of outrage that drives citizens ' politics the most away|ROOT\tthat it 's the climate of outrage that drives citizens ' politics the most away|ccomp\tthat drives citizens ' politics the most away|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is the leader of More Pais?",
                    "score": 0.4932,
                    "answers": "the leader of More País , who also does n't believe that it 's the climate of outrage that drives citizens ' politics the most away|nsubj\tof More País|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "“When the Titanic is sinking, no one cares that people insult themselves from cabins,” he claims.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com say no one cares about when the Titanic is sinking?",
                    "answer": "insult themselves"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the website that claims that people insult themselves from cabins when the Titanic is sinking?",
                    "score": 0.7431,
                    "answers": "people|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com say about the sinking of the Titanic?",
                    "score": 0.7059,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep\tthat|mark\tis|aux\t,|punct\tno|det\tthat|mark\t,|punct"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the names of the cabins where people insult themselves from?",
                    "score": 0.6938,
                    "answers": "cabins|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "What Titanic is that? A policy, he argues, incapable of giving answers to a “world that is chaos” and that “every day it announces historical agreements without people seeing that it improves their lives”.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did elpais.com report that What Titanic is that?",
                    "answer": "19/12/2020"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did elpais.com say was incapable of giving answers to a world that is chaos?",
                    "answer": "“every day it announces historical agreements without people seeing that it improves their lives”"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did elpais.com say about the Titanic policy?",
                    "score": 0.71,
                    "answers": "people seeing that it improves their lives|pcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com say about historical agreements?",
                    "score": 0.6141,
                    "answers": "A policy , he argues , incapable of giving answers to a “ world that is chaos ” and that “ every day it announces historical agreements without people seeing that it improves their lives ”|ROOT\tincapable of giving answers to a “ world that is chaos ” and that “ every day it announces historical agreements without people seeing that it improves their lives|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the history of the world that is chaos?",
                    "score": 0.5814,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep\tthat|mark\tWhat|det\tWhat Titanic|nsubj\tthat What Titanic is that ?|ccomp\tthat|attr\t?|attr\tA|det\t,|punct\the|nsubj\t, he argues ,|parataxis\t,|punct\tanswers|dobj\ta|det\t“|punct\tthat|nsubj\tthat is chaos ”|relcl\tchaos|attr\t”|punct\tand|cc\tthat|mark\t“|punct\tevery|det\tit|nsubj\tpeople|nsubj\tthat|mark\tit|nsubj\ttheir|poss\t”|punct"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.453,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that What Titanic is that ?|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "“Instead of bringing everyday life, politics is locked in an endogamic debate between politicians and journalists, while people go to hell,” he says.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did elpais.com report that politics is locked in an endogamic debate between politicians and journalists?",
                    "answer": "19/12/2020"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com say about politics?",
                    "score": 0.5328,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that “ Instead of bringing everyday life , politics is locked in an endogamic debate between politicians and journalists , while people go to hell|ccomp\telpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that “ Instead of bringing everyday life , politics is locked in an endogamic debate between politicians and journalists , while people go to hell , ” he says|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between politics and journalism?",
                    "score": 0.5277,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep\tthat|mark\t“|punct\tInstead|advmod\tInstead of bringing everyday life|prep\tbringing everyday life|pcomp\teveryday|amod\teveryday life|dobj\t,|punct\tpolitics|nsubjpass\tis|auxpass\tthat “ Instead of bringing everyday life , politics is locked in an endogamic debate between politicians and journalists , while people go to hell|ccomp\tin an endogamic debate between politicians and journalists|prep\tan|det\tendogamic|amod\tan endogamic debate between politicians and journalists|pobj\tand|cc\t,|punct\twhile|mark\tpeople|nsubj\twhile people go to hell|advcl\tto hell|prep\thell|pobj\t,|punct\t”|punct\the|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Gabriel Elorriaga, with many years of service in the PP, looks at the British Parliament and the “magnificent” documents with which he prepares his debates.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that Gabriel Elorriaga looked at the British Parliament and the “magnificent” documents with which he prepares his debates?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What documents did Gabriel Elorriaga prepare for debates?",
                    "score": 0.7701,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Gabriel Elorriaga , with many years of service in the PP , looks at the British Parliament and the “ magnificent ” documents with which he prepares his debates|ROOT\tthat Gabriel Elorriaga , with many years of service in the PP , looks at the British Parliament and the “ magnificent ” documents with which he prepares his debates|ccomp\tthe “ magnificent ” documents with which he prepares his debates|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Gabriel Elorriaga do to prepare his debates?",
                    "score": 0.7082,
                    "answers": "with many years of service in the PP|prep\tmany years of service in the PP|pobj\tof service in the PP|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Gabriel Elorriaga's role in the PP?",
                    "score": 0.6226,
                    "answers": "service in the PP|pobj\tin the PP|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Gabriel Elorriaga?",
                    "score": 0.5897,
                    "answers": "Gabriel Elorriaga , with many years of service in the PP ,|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Gabriel Elorriaga and the British Parliament?",
                    "score": 0.5818,
                    "answers": "Gabriel|compound\t“|punct\tmagnificent|amod\t”|punct\the|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "“There is very little debate on documents here,” he says, another symptom of a policy that the popular MP sees anchored in “very superficial debates”.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported on 19/12/2020 that \"There is very little debate on documents here\"?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the policy that the popular MP sees anchored in \"very superficial debates?",
                    "score": 0.6961,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tthat|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many debates are there each year?",
                    "score": 0.6676,
                    "answers": "in “ very superficial debates|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the debate on documents?",
                    "score": 0.6274,
                    "answers": "very little debate on documents|attr\ton documents|prep\tdocuments|pobj\there|advmod\tanchored in “ very superficial debates|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "“The orderly, rigorous debate doesn't work.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that \"The orderly, rigorous debate\" didn't work?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com say about the debate?",
                    "score": 0.7162,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tdoes|aux"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the definition of a rigorous debate?",
                    "score": 0.6751,
                    "answers": "rigorous|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the meaning of the orderly, rigorous debate?",
                    "score": 0.673,
                    "answers": "orderly|amod\tThe orderly , rigorous debate|nsubj\tthat “ The orderly , rigorous debate does n't work|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the debate that doesn't work?",
                    "score": 0.6315,
                    "answers": "n't|neg"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.4819,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that “ The orderly , rigorous debate does n't work|ROOT\ton 19/12/2020|prep\tThe|det\t,|punct"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "When we discuss the education law, we discuss religion or language, not school failure or the quality of teaching.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that when we discuss education law, we discuss religion or language?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com discuss education law?",
                    "score": 0.7103,
                    "answers": "that When we discuss the education law , we discuss religion or language , not school failure or the quality of teaching|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the quality of teaching in education law?",
                    "score": 0.7087,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the education law?",
                    "score": 0.6963,
                    "answers": "When we discuss the education law|advcl\tthe education law|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com say about education law?",
                    "score": 0.6683,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tWhen|advmod\twe|nsubj\tthe|det\t,|punct\twe|nsubj\t,|punct\tnot|neg\tthe|det"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "To this “denaturalization of politics,” says Elorriaga, “the profiles of representatives have contributed so much” that “too many years have passed without an institutional response to major problems”.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did elpais.com report on the denaturalization of politics?",
                    "answer": "19/12/2020"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Elorriaga say about denationalization of politics?",
                    "score": 0.7142,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that To this “ denaturalization of politics , ” says Elorriaga , “ the profiles of representatives have contributed so much ” that “ too many years have passed without an institutional response to major problems ”|ROOT\ton 19/12/2020|prep\tthat|mark\tTo this “ denaturalization of politics|prep\tthis|det\tthis “ denaturalization of politics|pobj\tpolitics|pobj\t,|punct\tsays Elorriaga ,|parataxis\t,|punct\tthe|det\tthe profiles of representatives|nsubj\trepresentatives|pobj\thave|aux\tso|advmod\tthat|mark\ttoo|advmod\ttoo many|amod\thave|aux\twithout an institutional response to major problems|prep\tan|det\tan institutional response to major problems|pobj\tmajor|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many years have passed without an institutional response to major problems?",
                    "score": 0.5785,
                    "answers": "“|punct\tof politics|prep\t”|punct\t“|punct\tof representatives|prep\tthat To this “ denaturalization of politics , ” says Elorriaga , “ the profiles of representatives have contributed so much ” that “ too many years have passed without an institutional response to major problems ”|ccomp\tso much ” that “ too many years have passed without an institutional response to major problems|dobj\t”|punct\t“|punct\ttoo many years|nsubj\tthat “ too many years have passed without an institutional response to major problems|acl\tinstitutional|amod\tto major problems|prep\tmajor problems|pobj\t”|punct"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "One case: unemployment, that eternal Spanish anomaly.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported on unemployment on 19/12/2020?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the current rate of unemployment in the United States?",
                    "score": 0.7802,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that One case : unemployment , that eternal Spanish anomaly|ROOT\ton 19/12/2020|prep\t19/12/2020|pobj\tthat|det\tOne|nummod\t:|punct\t,|punct\tthat|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between unemployment and eternal Spanish anomaly?",
                    "score": 0.676,
                    "answers": "eternal|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is unemployment?",
                    "score": 0.6659,
                    "answers": "that One case : unemployment , that eternal Spanish anomaly|dobj\tunemployment , that eternal Spanish anomaly|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the eternal Spanish anomaly?",
                    "score": 0.6225,
                    "answers": "that eternal Spanish anomaly|appos"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Jose María Maravall, Minister of Education in the first government of Felipe González, sounds very familiar some things that he has heard say these days about the law Celaá.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did elpais.com report that Jose Mara Maravall was the Minister of Education in the first government of Felipe González?",
                    "answer": "19/12/2020"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Jose María Maravall say these days about the law Celaá?",
                    "score": 0.6691,
                    "answers": "say these days|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Jose María Maravall?",
                    "score": 0.5522,
                    "answers": "Jose María Maravall , Minister of Education in the first government of Felipe González ,|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the first government of Felipe González?",
                    "score": 0.5475,
                    "answers": "the first government of Felipe González|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "“But they were not memories of 84, they were from the Middle Ages,” jokes who also endured an alluvial against his educational reform.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What type of soil did elpais endure against his educational reforms?",
                    "answer": "alluvial"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of alluvial against Johnson's educational reform?",
                    "score": 0.6143,
                    "answers": "But|cc\tnot|neg\tthe|det\twho|nsubj\talso|advmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the history of education reform?",
                    "score": 0.6071,
                    "answers": "his educational reform|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How old were the students who were in the Middle Ages?",
                    "score": 0.5758,
                    "answers": "of 84|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the dates of the Middle Ages?",
                    "score": 0.5035,
                    "answers": "from the Middle Ages|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the fondness of old students from the Middle Ages?",
                    "score": 0.4996,
                    "answers": "But they were not memories of 84|ccomp\tmemories of 84|attr"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Handed over for years to a productive career as a sociologist, Maravall already wrote in 2008 a book entitled Political Confrontation.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported on Maravall's book on 19/12/2020?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Did Maravall write a book entitled Political Confrontation?",
                    "score": 0.7808,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Handed over for years to a productive career as a sociologist , Maravall already wrote in 2008 a book entitled Political Confrontation|ROOT\tover|prt"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Did Maravall write Political Confrontation?",
                    "score": 0.7801,
                    "answers": "that Handed over for years to a productive career as a sociologist , Maravall already wrote in 2008 a book entitled Political Confrontation|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How long has Maravall been a sociologist?",
                    "score": 0.7048,
                    "answers": "for years|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What book did Maravall write in 2008?",
                    "score": 0.6864,
                    "answers": "a book entitled Political Confrontation|dobj\tentitled Political Confrontation|acl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Maravall's career as a sociologist?",
                    "score": 0.6333,
                    "answers": "a productive career as a sociologist|pobj\ta sociologist|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In it he compared the climates of crisis in the last González legislature and in the first of Jose Luis Rodríguez Zapatero.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that he compared the climates of crisis in the last González legislature and in the first of Jose Luis Rodrguez Zapatero?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the climate of crisis in the last González legislature and in the first of Jose Luis Rodríguez Zapatero?",
                    "score": 0.6444,
                    "answers": "and|cc"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Zapatero's was especially raw.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did elpais.com report that Zapatero's was particularly raw?",
                    "answer": "19/12/2020"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between Zapatero and Cubans?",
                    "score": 0.7555,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep\tthat|mark\t's|case\tthat Zapatero 's was especially raw|ccomp\tespecially|advmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Zapatero's raw state?",
                    "score": 0.7239,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Zapatero 's was especially raw|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the raw nature of Zapatero's?",
                    "score": 0.7226,
                    "answers": "especially raw|acomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In an advance of what would be the tactics of post-truth, a part of the political and media right tried to implicate the PSOE in a conspiracy around the massacres of 11-M. A socialist leader of the time recounts 16 major demonstrations in six years against the government's anti-terrorist policy.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How many demonstrations did a socialist leader recount in six years?",
                    "answer": "16"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What tactics did the political and media right use to try to implicate the PSOE?",
                    "score": 0.7376,
                    "answers": "of what would be the tactics of post - truth|prep\twhat would be the tactics of post - truth|pcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many demonstrations were there in the past six years against the anti-terrorist policy?",
                    "score": 0.6049,
                    "answers": "16 major demonstrations in six years against the government 's anti - terrorist policy|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the conspiracy around the massacres of 11-M.?",
                    "score": 0.6001,
                    "answers": "a part of the political and media right|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the government's anti-terrorist policy?",
                    "score": 0.5426,
                    "answers": "against the government 's anti - terrorist policy|prep\tthe government 's anti - terrorist policy|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who was the socialist leader of the time?",
                    "score": 0.514,
                    "answers": "A socialist leader of the time|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "And remember scenes that have not yet been reached, such as the assault on then Defense Minister Jose Bono in a march for the victims.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on the assault on Jose Bono?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the assault on then Defense Minister Jose Bono?",
                    "score": 0.5815,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that And remember scenes that have not yet been reached , such as the assault on then Defense Minister Jose Bono in a march for the victims|ROOT\tthat And remember scenes that have not yet been reached , such as the assault on then Defense Minister Jose Bono in a march for the victims|ccomp\tscenes that have not yet been reached , such as the assault on then Defense Minister Jose Bono in a march for the victims|dobj\thave|aux\tnot|neg\tyet|advmod\tbeen|auxpass\tsuch|amod\tsuch as the assault on then Defense Minister Jose Bono in a march for the victims|prep\tthe assault on then Defense Minister Jose Bono in a march for the victims|pobj\tthen|advmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of the assault that Jose Bono committed?",
                    "score": 0.5392,
                    "answers": "Jose|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the date of the assault on Jose Bono?",
                    "score": 0.5388,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep\tthat have not yet been reached|relcl\ton then Defense Minister Jose Bono|prep\tthen Defense Minister Jose Bono|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who was Jose Bono?",
                    "score": 0.5248,
                    "answers": "then Defense Minister|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "“Cryspation occurs every time the PSOE rules and disappears when the PP rules,” says Maravall, who analyzes the current moment as a further continuation of that trend, in some cases with recurring issues such as the already disappeared ETA.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that \"Cryspation occurs every time the PSOE rules and disappears when the PP rules\"?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What happens to ETA when the PP rules are broken?",
                    "score": 0.5459,
                    "answers": "disappears when the PP rules|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between the PSOE and ETA?",
                    "score": 0.4953,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that “ Cryspation occurs every time the PSOE rules and disappears when the PP rules|ccomp\tthat “ Cryspation occurs every time the PSOE rules and disappears when the PP rules|ccomp\tevery time the PSOE rules|npadvmod\tthe PSOE|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Cryspation?",
                    "score": 0.4914,
                    "answers": "Cryspation|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the current trend of ETA?",
                    "score": 0.4894,
                    "answers": "who analyzes the current moment as a further continuation of that trend , in some cases with recurring issues such as the already disappeared ETA|relcl\tfurther|amod\tthat trend|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many issues have disappeared ETA?",
                    "score": 0.4816,
                    "answers": "recurring|amod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "What he sees now is “more noise, because everything has spread more, in that situation it is more difficult to answer [the attacks] and there are the fake news, a form of deterioration of democracy”.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that what he sees now is more noise, because everything has spread more, in that situation it is more difficult to answer the attacks?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the effect of fake news on democracy?",
                    "score": 0.6195,
                    "answers": "of deterioration of democracy|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the purpose of fake news?",
                    "score": 0.5899,
                    "answers": "to answer [ the attacks ]|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the purpose of the fake news?",
                    "score": 0.5884,
                    "answers": "the attacks|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between fake news and democracy?",
                    "score": 0.5668,
                    "answers": "that What he sees now is “ more noise , because everything has spread more , in that situation it is more difficult to answer [ the attacks ] and there are the fake news , a form of deterioration of democracy ”|ccomp\tin that situation it is more difficult to answer [ the attacks ] and there are the fake news , a form of deterioration of democracy ”|conj\tthere are the fake news , a form of deterioration of democracy ”|conj\tthe fake news , a form of deterioration of democracy|attr\ta form of deterioration of democracy|appos\tdeterioration of democracy|pobj\tof democracy|prep\tdemocracy|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the noise from fake news?",
                    "score": 0.5498,
                    "answers": "more noise|attr"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "And with another difference: “The PSOE always had a competitor on the left.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that the PSOE always had a competitor on the left?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many competitors did the PSOE have on the left?",
                    "score": 0.7099,
                    "answers": "“ The PSOE always had a competitor on the left|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between PSOE and the PSOE?",
                    "score": 0.6371,
                    "answers": "The PSOE|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is on the left side of the PSOE team?",
                    "score": 0.6218,
                    "answers": "the left|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "But the PP never had a pressure like now with Vox.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that The PP never had a pressure like now with Vox?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What pressure did the PP face in 2020?",
                    "score": 0.7342,
                    "answers": "a|det\ta pressure like now|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between the PP and Vox?",
                    "score": 0.5389,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that But the PP never had a pressure like now with Vox|ROOT\ton 19/12/2020|prep\tthat|mark\tBut|cc\tthe|det\tnever|neg\tthat But the PP never had a pressure like now with Vox|ccomp\tlike now|prep\tnow|pcomp\twith Vox|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Further in time Juan Carlos Monedero, founder of Podemos and director of his foundation, goes: “What we are seeing on the right is the continuity of a tradition.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that Juan Carlos Monedero was the founder of Podemos?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Who founded Podemos and director of his foundation?",
                    "score": 0.6881,
                    "answers": "Juan|compound\tCarlos|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Juan Carlos Monedero say about the tradition of Podemos?",
                    "score": 0.6532,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tFurther|advmod\t,|punct\tand|cc\t,|punct\t:|punct\t“|punct\tthe|det\tthe|det\ta|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the history of Juan Carlos Monedero's foundation?",
                    "score": 0.6191,
                    "answers": "of his foundation|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between Juan Carlos Monedero and Podemos?",
                    "score": 0.5831,
                    "answers": "Further in time|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Juan Carlos Monedero?",
                    "score": 0.5534,
                    "answers": "Juan Carlos Monedero , founder of Podemos and director of his foundation ,|nsubj\tfounder of Podemos and director of his foundation|appos\tdirector of his foundation|conj\this|poss\this foundation|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The Spanish right is doctrinal, traditionalist, very nineteenth.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that The Spanish right is doctrinal, traditionalist, and very nineteenth century?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the basis of the Spanish right?",
                    "score": 0.696,
                    "answers": "The Spanish right|nsubj\tthat The Spanish right is doctrinal , traditionalist , very nineteenth|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com say about the Spanish right?",
                    "score": 0.6762,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that The Spanish right is doctrinal , traditionalist , very nineteenth|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between the Spanish right and traditionalist?",
                    "score": 0.6742,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep\tthat|mark\tThe|det\tdoctrinal|amod\t,|punct\ttraditionalist|amod\t,|punct\tvery|advmod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Since the 19th century he has cultivated the image of the inner enemy.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that he has cultivated the image of the inner enemy?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com say about his inner enemy?",
                    "score": 0.548,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did elpais.com say about the inner enemy?",
                    "score": 0.5324,
                    "answers": "that Since the 19th century he has cultivated the image of the inner enemy|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the history of Ilpais' image of the inner enemy?",
                    "score": 0.5255,
                    "answers": "Since the 19th century|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the inner enemy?",
                    "score": 0.5246,
                    "answers": "the inner enemy|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.4574,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Since the 19th century he has cultivated the image of the inner enemy|ROOT\tthat|mark\tthe|det\the|nsubj\thas|aux\tthe|det\tthe|det\tinner|amod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "“They are the CEDA of 34 fed by the media that are pulling it,” he concludes.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that “They are the CEDA of 34 fed by the media that are pulling it”?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the CEDA of 34 fed by the media?",
                    "score": 0.5794,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tThey|nsubj\tthe|det\tthe|det\tthat|nsubj\tare|aux\tit|dobj\t,|punct\the|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the CEDA?",
                    "score": 0.5509,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that “ They are the CEDA of 34 fed by the media that are pulling it|ccomp\ton 19/12/2020|prep\t“|punct\tthat “ They are the CEDA of 34 fed by the media that are pulling it|ccomp\tthe CEDA of 34 fed by the media that are pulling it|attr\tof 34 fed by the media|prep\t34 fed by the media|pobj\tfed by the media|acl\tby the media|agent\tthe media|pobj\tthat are pulling it|relcl\t”|punct\telpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that “ They are the CEDA of 34 fed by the media that are pulling it , ” he concludes|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Some of those media and those communicators in permanent war with the left were already there in the 1990s.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that some of the media and communicators in permanent war with the left were already there in the 1990s?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many communicators were there in the 1990s?",
                    "score": 0.5426,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep\tthose|det\tthose|det\talready|advmod\tthere|advmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What were the communicators in the 1990s?",
                    "score": 0.5054,
                    "answers": "those communicators in permanent war with the left|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between the media and the left in the 1990s?",
                    "score": 0.4516,
                    "answers": "those media and those communicators in permanent war with the left|pobj\tpermanent war with the left|pobj\tthat Some of those media and those communicators in permanent war with the left were already there in the 1990s|ccomp\tin the 1990s|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.3476,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Some of those media and those communicators in permanent war with the left were already there in the 1990s|ROOT\tand|cc"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "And they also accused González of ending the division of powers and endangering democracy.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did elpais.com report that González was accused of ending the division of powers?",
                    "answer": "19/12/2020"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who did elpais.com accuse of ending the division of powers?",
                    "answer": "González"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was González's role in ending the division of powers?",
                    "score": 0.6916,
                    "answers": "the division of powers|dobj\tof powers|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between González and democracy?",
                    "score": 0.609,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that And they also accused González of ending the division of powers and endangering democracy|ROOT\ton 19/12/2020|prep\tthey|nsubj\tthat And they also accused González of ending the division of powers and endangering democracy|ccomp\tof ending the division of powers and endangering democracy|prep\tpowers|pobj\tendangering democracy|conj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In 2007, in the midst of the PP's offensive against Zapatero, an article by political scientist Lourdes Lopez Nieto in the FAES magazine echoed the left's speech: “Crispation is what the PSOE says the right wing does when it competes electorally”.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that in the midst of the PP's offensive against Zapatero, an article by political scientist Lourdes Lopez Nieto in the FAES magazine echoed the left's speech?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Lourdes Lopez Nieto say in 2007 about the PP offensive against Zapatero?",
                    "score": 0.7582,
                    "answers": "an article by political scientist Lourdes Lopez Nieto in the FAES magazine|nsubj\tby political scientist Lourdes Lopez Nieto|prep\tpolitical scientist Lourdes Lopez Nieto|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was Lourdes Lopez Nieto's speech against Zapatero in 2007?",
                    "score": 0.708,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that In 2007 , in the midst of the PP 's offensive against Zapatero , an article by political scientist Lourdes Lopez Nieto in the FAES magazine echoed the left 's speech|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Lourdes Lopez Nieto's political affiliation?",
                    "score": 0.628,
                    "answers": "political scientist|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Feijoo also turns to Maravall's argument: “The tonic is always that when he rules the left he opposes the opposition rather than rule.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that Feijoo turned to Maravall's argument on 19/12/2020?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Feijoo say about Maravall's opposition?",
                    "score": 0.7019,
                    "answers": "that|mark\talso|advmod\t's|case\t:|punct\t“|punct\tThe|det\talways|advmod\tthat|mark\twhen|advmod\the|nsubj\tthe|det\tthe left|dobj\the|nsubj\tthe|det\trather|advmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Maravall's stance on opposing opposing opposition?",
                    "score": 0.6522,
                    "answers": "when he rules the left|advcl\tthat when he rules the left he opposes the opposition rather than rule|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Maravall and Feijoo?",
                    "score": 0.6147,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the tonic?",
                    "score": 0.5939,
                    "answers": "The tonic|nsubj\tThe tonic is always that when he rules the left he opposes the opposition rather than rule|acl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "And he gives an example: “De Aznar they said it was from the extreme right, from me they said I am from the extreme right, and now they say it also from Casado”.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did elpais.com report on 19/12/2020",
                    "answer": "“De Aznar they said it was from the extreme right, from me they said I am from the extreme right, and now they say it also from Casado”"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did de Aznar say about Casado?",
                    "score": 0.6517,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep\tthat|mark\tAnd|cc\tthat And he gives an example|ccomp\t:|punct\tthe|det\tme|pobj\tI|nsubj\tthe|det\tand|cc\tnow|advmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did De Aznar say about the extreme right?",
                    "score": 0.6263,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that And he gives an example : “ De Aznar they said it was from the extreme right , from me they said I am from the extreme right , and now they say it also from Casado ”|ROOT\tDe|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are de Aznar's views on the extreme right?",
                    "score": 0.5916,
                    "answers": ": “ De Aznar they said it was from the extreme right , from me they said I am from the extreme right , and now they say it also from Casado|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is de Aznar's political affiliation?",
                    "score": 0.5701,
                    "answers": "I am from the extreme right|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of de Aznar's extreme right?",
                    "score": 0.5536,
                    "answers": "from me|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Populars claim that they simply react to issues they consider very serious: the LAGs and corruption with González, the Statute and the negotiation with ETA with Zapatero, the pacts with the independents and the management of the pandemic now.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported on 19/12/2020 that Populars claim that they simply react to issues they consider very serious?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What are the pacts with the independents and the management of the pandemic?",
                    "score": 0.5606,
                    "answers": "of the pandemic|prep\tthe pandemic|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between González and ETA with Zapatero?",
                    "score": 0.5489,
                    "answers": "the LAGs and corruption with González , the Statute and the negotiation with ETA with Zapatero , the pacts with the independents and the management of the pandemic now|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is ETA's relationship with González?",
                    "score": 0.5415,
                    "answers": "with ETA|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are theacts with ETA and Zapatero?",
                    "score": 0.5395,
                    "answers": "the management of the pandemic now|conj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Elorriaga points out that, in times of tension, the left has also acted like this: “The Escraches to Soraya, the tides, the demonstrations surrounding the headquarters of the PP, the Never Most.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that Elorriaga pointed out that the left has also acted like this in times of tension?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Elorriaga say about the demonstrations surrounding the headquarters of the PP?",
                    "score": 0.5674,
                    "answers": "that Elorriaga points out that , in times of tension , the left has also acted like this : “ The Escraches to Soraya , the tides , the demonstrations surrounding the headquarters of the PP , the Never Most|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many times has the left acted like this during tension?",
                    "score": 0.5096,
                    "answers": "times of tension|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the purpose of the Escraches to Soraya demonstrations?",
                    "score": 0.5069,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Elorriaga points out that , in times of tension , the left has also acted like this : “ The Escraches to Soraya , the tides , the demonstrations surrounding the headquarters of the PP , the Never Most|ROOT\tlike this : “ The Escraches to Soraya , the tides , the demonstrations surrounding the headquarters of the PP , the Never Most|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "There are voices on the left that, while blaming the right, admit that in their field they cross interests in order not to lower the confrontation.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that there are voices on the left that admit that they cross interests in order to not lower the confrontation?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between the left and the right?",
                    "score": 0.4418,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that There are voices on the left that , while blaming the right , admit that in their field they cross interests in order not to lower the confrontation|ROOT\tthat|mark\tThere|expl\tthat|nsubj\t,|punct\twhile|mark\t,|punct\tthat|mark\tnot|neg\tto|aux\tthe confrontation|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "That old idea of the “doberman right” as a preferred opponent.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that That old idea of the “doberman right” was a preferred opponent?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does the \"doberman right\" mean?",
                    "score": 0.7943,
                    "answers": "of the “ doberman right ”|prep\tthe “ doberman right ”|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the old idea of the \"doberman right\" as a preferred opponent?",
                    "score": 0.7211,
                    "answers": "that That old idea of the “ doberman right ” as a preferred opponent|ccomp\tpreferred|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the origin of the phrase \"doberman right\"?",
                    "score": 0.6918,
                    "answers": "doberman|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the meaning of the \"doberman right\"?",
                    "score": 0.6902,
                    "answers": "as a preferred opponent|prep\ta|det\ta preferred opponent|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The Cruz evokes it, who, among the most current, points to the maneuvers of the United We can to torpedo the dialogue with Citizens.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that The Cruz evoked it?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the history of the maneuvers of the United States that torpedo the dialogue with Citizens?",
                    "score": 0.5193,
                    "answers": "who|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between the Trump administration and the Cuban people?",
                    "score": 0.481,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tThe|det\t,|punct\t,|punct\tthe|det\tmost|advmod\t,|punct\tthe|det\tthe|det\tWe|nsubj\tto|aux\tthe|det"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Errejon is clear: “The government is comfortable with the photo of Colon”.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that Errejon is clear: \"The government is comfortable with the photo of Colon\"?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the government say about the photo of colon?",
                    "score": 0.6644,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Errejon is clear : “ The government is comfortable with the photo of Colon ”|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the government's relationship with the photo of Colon?",
                    "score": 0.5956,
                    "answers": "”|punct"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Errejon's political affiliation with the colonist?",
                    "score": 0.5931,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Errejon?",
                    "score": 0.5662,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Errejon is clear|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Errejon and the government?",
                    "score": 0.553,
                    "answers": "that Errejon is clear|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Wallet leaves it on a question: “Did Sanchez ever care about growing Vox?”.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that Wallet left it on a question: “Did Sanchez ever care about growing Vox?”",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Did Sanchez care about growing the Vox?",
                    "score": 0.8574,
                    "answers": "Did Sanchez ever care about growing Vox|acl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the current growth rate of vox?",
                    "score": 0.7093,
                    "answers": "growing Vox|pcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Sanchez and Vox?",
                    "score": 0.6116,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Wallet leaves it on a question : “ Did Sanchez ever care about growing Vox ? ”|ROOT\ton 19/12/2020|prep\tthat|mark\tthat Wallet leaves it on a question : “ Did Sanchez ever care about growing Vox ?|ccomp\tit|dobj\ton a question : “ Did Sanchez ever care about growing Vox ?|prep\ta|det\t:|punct\t“|punct\tDid|aux\tever|advmod\tabout growing Vox|prep\t?|punct\t”|punct"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Nor does the founder of Podemos deny that the radicalization of the right is a reaction to Catalan independence: “We already told them in their day that they were awakening the beast of fascism”.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that Nor does the founder of Podemos deny that the radicalization of the right was a reaction to Catalan independence?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the radicalization of the right after Catalan independence?",
                    "score": 0.8174,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Nor does the founder of Podemos deny that the radicalization of the right is a reaction to Catalan independence : “ We already told them in their day that they were awakening the beast of fascism ”|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did the founder of Podemos say about radicalization of the right?",
                    "score": 0.7962,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020|ccomp\tthat|mark\tNor|cc\tdoes|aux\tthe|det\tthat|mark\tthe|det\tthe|det\ta|det\t:|punct\talready|advmod\tthem|dobj\tin their day|prep\ttheir|poss\tthat|mark\tthey|nsubj\twere|aux\tthe|det\tfascism|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who was the founder of Podemos?",
                    "score": 0.6939,
                    "answers": "the founder of Podemos|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In this climate of disquiet with the present, longing for the great leaderships of the past proliferates and a certain feeling that the level of politics has reached bottom.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that longing for the great leaderships of the past proliferates?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did elpais.com say about politics?",
                    "score": 0.5619,
                    "answers": "a certain feeling that the level of politics has reached bottom|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the current level of politics?",
                    "score": 0.5357,
                    "answers": "of politics|prep\tpolitics|pobj\tthat the level of politics has reached bottom|acl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.4028,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that In this climate of disquiet with the present , longing for the great leaderships of the past proliferates and a certain feeling that the level of politics has reached bottom|ROOT\ton 19/12/2020|prep\t,|punct"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Now politics has become a professional career,” says Anasagasti.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did elpais.com report that now politics has become a professional career?",
                    "answer": "19/12/2020"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What has politics become a professional career?",
                    "score": 0.79,
                    "answers": "that Now politics has become a professional career|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Anasagasti say about politics becoming a professional career?",
                    "score": 0.7839,
                    "answers": ",|punct"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of how politics has become a career?",
                    "score": 0.7491,
                    "answers": "politics|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com say about politics?",
                    "score": 0.6921,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Now politics has become a professional career , ” says Anasagasti|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the professional career of Anasagasti?",
                    "score": 0.6492,
                    "answers": "a professional career|attr"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "A very common thesis among the old socialist guard, of which Maravall disagrees: “Sánchez is the first president of the government who speaks English and is a doctor.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who disagrees with Sanchez's thesis?",
                    "answer": "Maravall"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the common thesis among the old socialist guard who speak English and is a doctor?",
                    "score": 0.6123,
                    "answers": "that A very common thesis among the old socialist guard , of which Maravall disagrees : “ Sánchez is the first president of the government who speaks English and is a doctor|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is the first president of the government who speaks English?",
                    "score": 0.5748,
                    "answers": "A|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Dr. Maravall disagrees with Sánchez?",
                    "score": 0.546,
                    "answers": "Sánchez is the first president of the government who speaks English and is a doctor|acl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Maravall's political affiliation?",
                    "score": 0.5298,
                    "answers": "of which Maravall disagrees|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Maravall disagrees with?",
                    "score": 0.5253,
                    "answers": "very common|amod\tamong the old socialist guard , of which Maravall disagrees|prep\tthe old socialist guard , of which Maravall disagrees|pobj\tof which|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "It's no small thing.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that It's no small thing?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.5311,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that It 's no small thing|ROOT\ton 19/12/2020|prep\tthat|mark\tIt|nsubj\tthat It 's no small thing|ccomp\tno|det\tsmall|amod\tno small thing|attr"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Iglesias holds a PhD in Political Science.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that Iglesias holds a PhD in Political Science?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Iglesias holding a PhD in Political Science?",
                    "score": 0.7778,
                    "answers": "that|mark\ta|det"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Alfonso Guerra had none”.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did elpais.com report that Alfonso Guerra had none?",
                    "answer": "19/12/2020"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Alfonso Guerra having none?",
                    "score": 0.7777,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Alfonso Guerra had none ”|ROOT\ton 19/12/2020|prep\tthat|mark\tAlfonso|compound\tthat Alfonso Guerra had none|ccomp\tnone|dobj\t”|punct"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The emergence of new parties has multiplied voices and intensified noise.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that the emergence of new parties has multiplied voices and intensified noise?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What has the emergence of new parties done for voices and increased noise?",
                    "score": 0.83,
                    "answers": "voices|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many new parties have been formed since the beginning of 2020?",
                    "score": 0.758,
                    "answers": "of new parties|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the new parties?",
                    "score": 0.6449,
                    "answers": "new parties|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the number of new parties in the country?",
                    "score": 0.6246,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.4546,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that The emergence of new parties has multiplied voices and intensified noise|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "“And the new one has to scream a little to make himself visible,” admits Wallet.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that \"And the new one has to scream a little to make himself visible\"?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How much does a new person scream to make himself visible?",
                    "score": 0.6676,
                    "answers": "a little|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the number of new coins in the world?",
                    "score": 0.5808,
                    "answers": "a|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does it mean to scream a little to make yourself visible?",
                    "score": 0.5671,
                    "answers": "that “ And the new one has to scream a little to make himself visible|ccomp\tto make himself visible|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does it take to make a new one visible?",
                    "score": 0.5654,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that “ And the new one has to scream a little to make himself visible , ” admits Wallet|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the new Wallet?",
                    "score": 0.4865,
                    "answers": "the new one|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "But, in the face of those who blame the appearance of their party for encanning the climate, the founder of Podemos replies: “On the contrary.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that the founder of Podemos replied to those who blamed the appearance of their party for encanning the climate?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Who founded Podemos?",
                    "score": 0.759,
                    "answers": "of Podemos|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What political party is Podemos affiliated with?",
                    "score": 0.6899,
                    "answers": "their party|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Podemos say about climate change?",
                    "score": 0.6878,
                    "answers": "on 19/12/2020|prep\tfor encanning the climate|prep\tencanning the climate|pcomp\tthe climate|dobj\tthe contrary|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did the founder of Podemos say about the appearance of their party?",
                    "score": 0.5979,
                    "answers": "the appearance of their party|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who was the founder of Podemos?",
                    "score": 0.5758,
                    "answers": "the founder of Podemos|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "We come from 15-M, we parliamentaryize the conflict, we take it from the street to Parliament.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that We come from 15-M, we parliamentaryize the conflict, we take the conflict from the street to Parliament?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com say about parliamentaryizing the conflict?",
                    "score": 0.5884,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tWe|nsubj\t-|punct\t,|punct\twe|nsubj\tthe|det\t,|punct\twe|nsubj\tit|dobj\tthe|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the purpose of parliamentaryizing the conflict?",
                    "score": 0.5571,
                    "answers": "we parliamentaryize the conflict|ccomp\tthe conflict|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the difference between parliamentaryize the conflict and Parliament?",
                    "score": 0.5153,
                    "answers": "the street|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of where the meeting took place?",
                    "score": 0.4392,
                    "answers": "that We come from 15 - M , we parliamentaryize the conflict , we take it from the street to Parliament|ccomp\tfrom the street|prep\tto Parliament|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between 15-M and Parliament?",
                    "score": 0.4264,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that We come from 15 - M , we parliamentaryize the conflict , we take it from the street to Parliament|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Another thing is that we broke the pact of silence that there was on some issues: the Emeritus king, the traps of the electoral system, the chanchullos linked to bipartisanism, 3% of CiU. I'm sorry.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that We broke the pact of silence?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did elpais.com say about the breaking of the pact of silence?",
                    "answer": "I'm sorry"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did elpais.com say about the breaking of the pact of silence?",
                    "answer": "I'm sorry"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Who broke the pact of silence?",
                    "score": 0.5932,
                    "answers": "that we broke the pact of silence that there was on some issues : the Emeritus king , the traps of the electoral system , the chanchullos linked to bipartisanism , 3 % of CiU.|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the purpose of the pact of silence between the Emeritus king and the chanchullos linked to bipartisanism?",
                    "score": 0.5455,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tthat|mark\tthe|det\tthat|attr\tthere|expl\tsome|det\tthe|det\tthe|det\tthe|det\tthe|det\tI|nsubj\tsorry|acomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the traps of the electoral system?",
                    "score": 0.5248,
                    "answers": "the Emeritus king , the traps of the electoral system , the chanchullos linked to bipartisanism , 3 % of CiU.|appos\telectoral|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between the chanchullos and bipartisanism?",
                    "score": 0.5049,
                    "answers": "on some issues|prep\tbipartisanism|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between bipartisanism and the chanchullos?",
                    "score": 0.4997,
                    "answers": "linked to bipartisanism|acl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "“The future.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported on 19/12/2020?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com say about the future?",
                    "score": 0.5718,
                    "answers": "that “ The future|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.4569,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that “ The future|ROOT\ton 19/12/2020|prep\tthat|mark\t“|punct\tThe|det"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Is there any indication that this can change?Some loose impressions: Elorriaga bets on the PP forgetting Vox to build a speech of his own; Cruz hopes that the consolidation of the government after the Budgets will have a calming effect; Maravall is optimistic with the coalition executive, because “that is the most common type of government in the world and the one that distributes the income best”; Monedero fears that there will only be “noise, noise and noise”.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that Is there any indication that this can change?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Elorriaga bet on the PP forgetting for?",
                    "score": 0.7995,
                    "answers": "Elorriaga bets on the PP forgetting Vox to build a speech of his own|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Elorriaga say about the government after the Budgets?",
                    "score": 0.7731,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Is there any indication that this can change?Some loose impressions :|ccomp\tCruz hopes that the consolidation of the government after the Budgets will have a calming effect|ccomp\tthe consolidation of the government after the Budgets|nsubj\tof the government|prep\tthe government|pobj\tthat there will only be “ noise , noise and noise|ccomp\tnoise , noise and noise|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Elorriaga do to build a speech of his own?",
                    "score": 0.7647,
                    "answers": "on the PP forgetting Vox to build a speech of his own|prep\tthe PP forgetting Vox to build a speech of his own|pcomp\ta speech of his own|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Maravall's opinion on the government that distributes the income best?",
                    "score": 0.6973,
                    "answers": "Maravall is optimistic with the coalition executive , because “ that is the most common type of government in the world and the one that distributes the income best ”|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the most common type of government in the world?",
                    "score": 0.6157,
                    "answers": "because|mark\tmost common|amod\tthe most common type of government in the world and the one that distributes the income best ”|attr\tof government|prep\tgovernment|pobj\tin the world|prep\tthe world|pobj\tthe one that distributes the income best|conj\tthat distributes the income best|relcl\tnoise|conj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Errejon is concerned that this “client's act, bar bar, politics” is “the breeding ground for social trust to rot”.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 19/12/2020 that Errejon is concerned that client's act, bar bar, politics is \"the breeding ground for social trust to rot\"?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is Errejon's stance on bar bar bar politics?",
                    "score": 0.639,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 19/12/2020 that Errejon is concerned that this “ client 's act , bar bar , politics ” is “ the breeding ground for social trust to rot ”|ROOT\t's|case\tthis “ client 's act , bar bar , politics ”|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the purpose of bar bar, politics?",
                    "score": 0.6203,
                    "answers": "for social trust to rot|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Errejon say about the relationship between theclient act and bar bar, politics?",
                    "score": 0.6129,
                    "answers": "the breeding ground for social trust to rot|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between bar bar and politics?",
                    "score": 0.5843,
                    "answers": "bar bar|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Errejon's relationship with theclient's act, bar bar, politics?",
                    "score": 0.5513,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tthat|mark\tthis|det\t“|punct\t,|punct\t,|punct\t”|punct\t“|punct\tthe|det\tfor|mark\tto|aux\t”|punct"
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}